<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kiln:root xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
           xmlns:kiln="http://www.kcl.ac.uk/artshums/depts/ddh/kiln/ns/1.0"
           xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform">

  <kiln:parent>
    <xi:include href="base.xml" />
  </kiln:parent>

  <kiln:child>
    <kiln:block name="title">
      <xsl:text>About<kiln:super /></xsl:text>
    </kiln:block>

    <kiln:block name="page-header">
      <h1>About</h1>
    </kiln:block>

    <kiln:block name="content">
      <div class="span12">
        <h3><strong>About this edition</strong></h3>

        <p>This prototype edition features a representative range of
        dramatic records, collected by Jessica Freeman, that pertain
        to the Fortune theatre on Golding Lane, north of the London
        City wall. The Fortune was built in 1600 and operated until
        the mid-17th century. Our prototype does not include every
        Fortune theatre record that will eventually appear in Dr
        Freeman’s Middlesex collection in the REED series, but the
        records here have served as a useful sample for development of
        a new online production environment for REED editorial staff,
        experimentation with TEI markup of complex texts, digital
        indexing of persons and places, and linking with related data
        in REED’s <em>Early Modern London Theatres</em> and
        <em>Patrons and Performances</em> websites.</p>

        <p>The public interface for this Fortune Theatre Records
        project is intended to share initial results of our
        collaboration and to give our users an early glimpse of some
        aspects of the form a digital REED collection might take.</p>

        <p>We are pleased to make freely available the Fortune Theatre
        TEI records in a ZIP file on the REED information website,
        linked <a
        href="http://www.reed.utoronto.ca/FortuneDirectory.zip">here</a>. The
        data is licensed under a Creative Commons
        Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License.</p>

        <p>Fuller details of the project are provided in the partners’
        <a
        href="http://www.reed.utoronto.ca/FortuneWhitePaper.pdf">white
        paper</a>, also on the REED website. We welcome contact and
        suggestions.</p>

        <h3><strong>What the prototype does not include</strong></h3>

        <p>The Fortune Theatre Records is a draft selection of
        dramatic records only, not intended to be as comprehensive or
        as thoroughly vetted as a typical REED edition. The Records
        text has been transcribed according to long-established REED
        editorial principles and checked in paleographical
        detail. Document descriptions and textual notes are here
        linked directly with their records. However, the user will not
        find a full Introduction, Translations, or Glossaries and the
        Endnotes remain a work in progress, so only those drafts
        contributed by the editor are linked with their records.</p>

        <p>At present, as part of our experimental process, we have
        enabled searching the Records via only selected facets for
        people, places, troupes, and play titles on the left side of
        the screen.</p>

        <h3><strong>About REED</strong></h3>

        <p>The Records of Early English Drama (REED) is an
        international humanities research project whose aim is to
        find, transcribe, and publish original records of English
        dramatic and other secular entertainment from earliest times
        to 1642. From the beginning, the principal product of the REED
        enterprise has been the conventional print volume, now
        numbering 33, with another set of volumes in production for
        <em>Civic London to 1558</em>. REED’s main focus has, of
        necessity, been directed toward activities related to the
        ongoing, regular production of volumes in the series. This has
        meant that only limited resources, both in terms of staff time
        and funding, could be allocated to implementing the digital
        transformation of its primary output, which REED sees as a
        critical change, essential to its future role in
        scholarship.</p>

        <p>In recent years REED has been working in deliberate steps
        towards the transition from a traditional editorial project
        producing a print series to a digital humanities-oriented
        project producing <a
        href="http://www.reed.utoronto.ca/"><em>REED Online</em></a>,
        a web-accessible repository of all REED’s resources. At
        present there are two research and educational datasets
        available as open access websites: <a
        href="http://link.library.utoronto.ca/reed/"><em>Patrons and
        Performances</em></a>, launched in 2003 in partnership with
        the University of Toronto Libraries, and <a
        href="http://www.emlot.kcl.ac.uk/"><em>Early Modern London
        Theatres</em></a>, launched in 2011 in partnership with the
        Department of Digital Humanities, King’s College London (DDH)
        and the University of Southampton. REED is now determined to
        revolutionize its production processes in order to deliver
        forthcoming county and city collections as fully searchable,
        interactive online editions linked with other resources on the
        internet and integrated with its own current digital projects,
        <em>Patrons and Performances </em>and EMLoT.</p>

        <p>There has been considerable exploration of the components
        of this digital future, first through a NEH Digital Humanities
        Startup grant (2007–9) and then thanks to a SSHRC-funded 2011
        workshop ‘Envisioning REED in the Digital Age’ that brought
        together 20 digital humanists to advise and bring fresh
        perspectives to the challenge of moving REED fully online. The
        2012 grant from the Mellon Foundation for the Fortune Theatre
        Records prototype has amply demonstrated and tested some of
        the essential features of the online editorial production
        processes and moved REED significantly closer to realizing its
        digital goals.</p>
      </div>
    </kiln:block>

  </kiln:child>
</kiln:root>
