<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kiln:root xmlns:kiln="http://www.kcl.ac.uk/artshums/depts/ddh/kiln/ns/1.0"
           xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
           xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform">

  <kiln:parent>
    <xi:include href="base.xml" />
  </kiln:parent>

  <kiln:child>
    <kiln:block name="title">
      <xsl:text>Team and Sponsor<kiln:super /></xsl:text>
    </kiln:block>

    <kiln:block name="page-header">
      <h1>Team and Sponsor</h1>
    </kiln:block>

    <kiln:block name="content">
      <div class="span12">
        <h3>The Fortune Theatre Records: A Prototype Digital Edition
        by Records of Early English Drama (REED) could not have been
        created without the help of the following institutions and
        individuals, whose contributions are gratefully
        acknowledged:</h3>

        <p><strong>Financial Sponsor</strong></p>

        <p>This Prototype Digital Edition was made possible by the
        generous support of the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation through
        its Scholarly Communications Program.</p>

        <p><strong>Research Team</strong></p>

        <p>University of Toronto</p>

        <ul>
          <li>Sally-Beth MacLean (REED), Principal Investigator; editorial direction</li>
          <li>Carolyn Black (REED), Senior Editorial Consultant</li>
          <li>John A. Geck (REED), Project Manager</li>
          <li>Patrick Gregory (REED), Paleographer</li>
          <li>Tanya Hagen (REED), Bibliographer and editor of Early Modern London Theatre (EMLoT) Fortune Theatre records</li>
          <li>Sian Meikle (University of Toronto Libraries), Interim Director, Information Technology Services - Digital Library &amp; Web Services; Partner</li>
        </ul>
        <p> King’s College London</p>
        <ul>
          <li>John Bradley (Department of Digital Humanities, DDH), Partner; technical direction</li>
          <li>Paul Caton (DDH), TEI/XML consultant and Entity Authority Tool Set (EATS) data design for records data</li>
          <li>Miguel Vieira (DDH), prototype web application creator</li>
          <li>Paul Vetch (DDH), Partner; Boydell &amp; Brewer liaison; research development staff manager</li>
        </ul>
        <p> Ryerson University</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Jason Boyd (Centre for Digital Humanities), Partner; TEI Customization and Implementation; EATS implementation supervisor</li>
          <li>Trieneke Gastmeier, EATS implementation Research Assistant</li>
          <li>Daniela Robibero, Experiential Work Study Undergraduate Research Assistant</li>
        </ul>
        <p> Other Team Members</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Peter Clifford (Boydell and Brewer), Partner; Managing Director, Boydell and Brewer</li>
          <li>Stephanie Hovland, REED research associate paleographer</li>
          <li>Jessica Freeman, REED Middlesex/Westminster collection editor including Fortune Records</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Thanks also to Mike Stumpf for supplementary research on some of the Fortune Theatre records to facilitate EATS implementation.</p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">Server infrastructure has been kindly provided by the Department of Digital Humanities, King’s College London.</p>
      </div>
    </kiln:block>

  </kiln:child>
</kiln:root>
